JOSEPH PADFIELD FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

07789006300

joseph.padfield@gmail.com

portfolio | github | linkedin

SKILLS

HTML SQL
CSS Slim
Javascript React
PHP Git
Python Sass

JOB HISTORY

Not working due to illness

December 2022 - March 2024

Recruitment Consultant - Legal

Taylor Root

August 2022 - November 2022

My three months at Taylor Root were predominantly spent developing my knowledge of the legal market and building a candidate base, before being cut short.

Recruitment Consultant - Catastrophe Modeling and Exposure Management

Gravitas

January 2022 - August 2022

Worked with actuaries in a niche area of the insurance market, leveraging my communication skills to cultivate new business relationships with insurance companies in the US market. My first exposure to data science and python.

Opera Singer

2007 - 2021

Performed leading roles internationally with prestigious theatres and companies across the UK, France, South Africa and Canada, beginning alongside my studies.

See my website here for more details.

ABOUT

Full-stack developer with a passion for technology, recently graduated from iO Academy (Bath, UK).

Transitioned from a successful 12-year career as an opera singer, driven by a lifelong interest in software and a desire to expand my horizon..

Outside of work, I enjoy films (especially horror), reading, video games, and fitness.

Job history gap is due to illness. I am fully recovered and ready to return to professional life.

PROJECTS

I recently studied Full-Stack Software Development at iO Academy, during which time I worked on a range of projects, both individually and with a scrum team. Below is a selection that best represents my skills. Please see my portfolio sites for a complete list.

Job Listing Front End Website

Group front-end project using React and Bootstrap.
The API was provided. <u>Live link</u> <u>Github link</u>

Furniture Store API

Group back-end project using PHP and SQL. The front-end was provided. <u>Live link</u> <u>Github link</u>

Another Project

Description here and describe the tools that we used.

Live link Github link

EDUCATION

BPP Law School: PGDL, Law

2021

Guildhall School of Music and Drama: Artist Diploma, Music Performance, Opera - First 2013 - 2015

Guildhall School of Music and Drama: MPerf (Masters), Opera School - First 2011 - 2013

Guildhall School of Music and Drama: BMus(Hons), Music Performance, Opera – First 2007 - 2011